The art of moving to the country.
EN conflict text
Have you ever thought about moving to the country?
It's been almost ten years since I took that step - and I haven't regretted it.
null
Time goes by and everything is not as you imagined.
I was going to make a small series about what it is like to be a beginner in the country.
null
This first part will be an introduction.
Then I intend to address other topics such as:
null
Economy,
How to support themselves,
Buy farm
Gear, neighbors and much more.
I have many ideas.
null
If you come up with more ideas, write in the comments and I'll try to get it
On the list of things to do.
null
That said - it's pretty much ten years that I've had the farm now.
And everything has not been as I imagined.
But much has still fallen into place.
null
In the beginning when I had the farm - when I had just moved here full time.
So I went an education in Mathantverk
Then one of the first tasks was to paint with watercolors.
null
You would show with a picture what you thought it would look like in the future.
Much has actually become as I planned.
null
If you look on the map here you do not have to get stuck for the artistic qualities.
I know it's a masterpiece. But don't hook you up to it.
See what it represents instead.
null
In this picture I have included the dreams I had for the future.
You can see here: The beekeeping,
I have the pond with crayfish cultivation - it was not dug then.
The forest is gone and instead I have cultivations.
null
Rhubarb cultivation and apple orchard.
One sees the chickens and
null
Here I even got a bus stop.
One of the ideas I had.
All these things have actually been done.
null
Then not everything has become just as I thought.
I had three more hopes:
null
That I would be rich, powerful and an amazing lover.
Everything is not as you imagined,
But one in three is not so bad.
null
That said, this is supposed to be a series about what it is like to be a beginner in the country.
A lot of TV is done and is written a lot about how fantastic it is in the country.
null
But you only show the sunshine side.
I thought with this series try to give you the whole picture, as I experience it anyway.
null
And bring both - the good - and the evil.
(You may remember that TV series.)
null
I will also include the problems, it will not be exactly as you imagined.
There are disadvantages to living in the countryside.
null
Primarily practical: there are long distances
You usually pay higher taxes when you live in the countryside
null
And you usually get worse service.
There is worse public transport
null
Worse - or at least longer for healthcare.
The time to get an ambulance here is considerably longer than in Stockholm.
null
This is what you have to live with, part of the decision to move to the country.
There are still lots of qualities.
null
The great quality of living in the countryside is freedom.
You have freedom and a huge number of opportunities to do things like you want to do yourself
And that is difficult to do in town.
null
If you live in a residential area, it can even be difficult to have chickens if the neighbors complain.
Here you can get chickens - start a beekeeping without anyone protesting.
null
You can get lots of animals if you are interested.
If you are interested in cultivation, you can do so in a variety of scales.
You can have your little garden where you grow your own apple tree
Or you can turn big.
Everything depends on what you want to do yourself.
If you, like me, are a beginner in the country, it requires a lot of adjustments.
Above all to think about
To start thinking about things you didn't do before.
null
For example, there is no property manager.
If a tube freezes in the barn during the winter, you have to deal with it.
null
And you have to deal with it directly.
If an animal gets sick or injured, it is you who must handle that situation.
And you have to handle it directly.
null
I thought a little bit when I moved out that it would be a more stress -free environment in the country.
And that's it in many ways-
Especially because I decide for myself what to do, and when I have to do it.
By and large.
But when things happen, you have to deal with it.
There is no one else to turn to.
Not in the first stage anyway.
You must take responsibility yourself.
null
This can be seen as a disadvantage - or an advantage.
The advantage is that you feel that it is you control this yourself.
This is also the big difference between being a holiday residence in the countryside
null
Spending a few months in the summer cottage is not at all the same as living in the countryside.
Above all, you will notice the difference during the winter months.
null
When you have maybe half a year where most of the day consists of compact darkness.
My first winter out here was one of the first measures to set out outer lights.
null
So that you saw something outside the windows.
It is easy to feel claustrophobic otherwise.
You also have to get used to dealing with loneliness.
I have had no problems with that.
But if you are a very social person
null
So maybe it will be hard.
In the summer you can have visitors all the time
Not as many people want to visit the farm in January.
null
However, what you have - that you do not have in town - are the neighbors.
The neighbors!
I know pretty much all the neighbors here.
I didn't do that in Stockholm.
There I hardly knew who lived in the door next door.
null
Here you have some kind of contact with virtually all neighbors
And it's a real community.
null
We know each other and we hang out.
Not every day, not every week but regularly
null
So that you feel: if something happens, I can call the neighbors.
The neighbors are more important than authorities, municipalities, police and so on.
null
It is the neighbors who are first in place if something happens.
Like when the barn burned.
Then was not the police and fire brigade that came first - it was the neighbors.
null
This is a little taste of this series.
I've thought it will come out
null
once a week.
The goal is a section every weekend.
Do you like the idea so give me a thumbs up
null
And if you want to follow life in the yard and this series, please subscribe to this channel.
Hello then we will see you again soon.